<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-12-10T17:43:31+00:00</updated><id>https://jenniferisasi.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Dr. Jennifer Isasi&apos;s research portfolio. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Data We Can Touch: DHMakes and LEGO Visualization at Semester’s End</title><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/DHmakes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data We Can Touch: DHMakes and LEGO Visualization at Semester’s End"/><published>2025-04-22T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-22T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/DHmakes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/DHmakes/"><![CDATA[<p>As the semester draws to a close, we find ourselves collectively exhausted and racing to the finish line. Rather than pile on more theoretical concepts during this final push, I hosted a hands-on DHmakes session focused on the physicalization of data—offering a creative and fun conclusion to our Foundations in Digital Humanities course before final presentations.</p> <p>For this class, I deliberately paired minimal pedagogy with low-tech approaches and DHmakes principles—creating a learning environment that emphasized experimentation, tactile engagement, and accessible tools rather than complex digital platforms. This combination allowed students to focus on creativity while lightening the cognitive load during this demanding time of the semester. I can see it on their faces.</p> <p>The session drew inspiration from brilliant DHMakes practitioners whose work has illuminated our learning journey throughout the year: Pam, Quinn, Claudia, Alex, Amanda, Ryan, and many others who ingeniously blend craft with data visualization and share their creations under the #DHmakes hashtag on social media.</p> <h2 id="from-dissertation-to-physical-network">From Dissertation to Physical Network</h2> <p>We kicked off with a guest presentation by Dr. Sara Arribas Colmenar, who recently defended her dissertation. She showcased her physical network visualization project, walking us through her conceptual framework, methodological choices, DIY execution, and representational decisions. Her piece—created with wood, nails, floss, and paint during her summer research time in Spain, adapting a regular string art class—demonstrated what DHMakes can be at its best. She drew on the <em>Making Research Tactile: Critical Making and Data Physicalization in Digital Humanities Special Issue</em> of DH+Lib to showcase what DHMakes is, but explained how crafting a tangible representation of her digital networks actually improved her color choices in Gephi, basing her choices on accessibility for colorblindness.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/arribas-colmenar_dhmakes.jpg" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/arribas-colmenar_dhmakes.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Two insights from Sara’s presentation resonated deeply with students:</p> <ul> <li>Creating tangible representations of digital data can deepen our understanding of methods, algorithms, and visualizations beyond what’s possible in purely digital forms.</li> <li>DHMakes provides a way to momentarily “unplug” from traditional academic work through physical embodiment, even while advancing scholarship.</li> </ul> <h2 id="legos-as-data-visualization-tools">LEGOs as Data Visualization Tools</h2> <p>For the hands-on portion, I brought a small dataset capturing distances (in both miles and minutes) from our campus’s Old Main building to other important locations: the Stadium, Library, Ice-Cream store, and more. Then I introduced our medium for the day: LEGO bricks.</p> <p>Among countless approaches to physical data representation beautifully illustrated in Data@Urban’s article <a href="https://urban-institute.medium.com/bringing-data-to-life-physical-data-projects-at-urban-2afe193bd038">“Bringing Data to Life”</a>, LEGO offered a playful yet structured way to represent our academic environment—not just through architectural structures but by including the people who bring these spaces to life.</p> <p>We initially tried using one 1×1 brick per 4 minutes of travel time, but soon realized this wouldn’t give us enough granularity on the 32x32 plate we were using. All was packed together! So we pivoted to using one 1×1 brick per minute, with 4 being the minimum (nearest location) and 26 the maximum (to the Stadium).</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/dhmakes_lego-1.JPG" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/dhmakes_lego-1.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/dhmakes_lego-2.jpg" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/dhmakes_lego-2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>The resulting visualization was creative—perhaps a bit chaotic—but sparked a fascinating discussion and we have some laughs that we need right now. One student envisioned using LEGO bricks to teach spatial navigation, noting how students often lose their orientation when viewing spaces only through digital representations. Another one suggested it would be great to pick a Lego person and record it “walking” around campus to those locations, creating a video to pair up with the physical visualization we already had and asked: Is that DH?!</p> <h2 id="beyond-the-classroom">Beyond the Classroom</h2> <p>Our session evolved into a broader conversation about the importance of having hobbies during graduate school (and beyond!) that may or may not connect to research interests. If nothing else, the session demonstrated that incorporating play into academic work isn’t frivolous—returning to embodied activities, physical data representation, and tactile creativity offers valuable ways to learn, explore, teach, and innovate.</p> <p>In these final, pressure-filled weeks of the semester, our LEGO data visualization session provided not just a break from routine, but a reminder that digital humanities thrives when we connect the digital back to the human—hands, minds, and all.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="course"/><category term="course"/><category term="workshops"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the semester draws to a close, we find ourselves collectively exhausted and racing to the finish line. Rather than pile on more theoretical concepts during this final push, I hosted a hands-on DHmakes session focused on the physicalization of data—offering a creative and fun conclusion to our Foundations in Digital Humanities course before final presentations.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How has DH changed over the years and what does it entail?</title><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/evolution-of-DH-and-action/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How has DH changed over the years and what does it entail?"/><published>2025-01-21T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-21T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/evolution-of-DH-and-action</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/evolution-of-DH-and-action/"><![CDATA[<p>As difficult as it is to newcomers to accept the fact that the Digital Humanities lacks a firm definition (a student rightly asked for one again at the end of the class), we can easily see its evolution -so to speak- of our approaches to doing or practicing DH. Since we are going to be reading recent articles and they often mention past debates or issues, I wanted to give a quick preview of how we have all shaped DH to what it currently does.</p> <p>For students to learn about the last 10ish years or so of the digital humanities in, mostly, the United States, I assigned each of them one of the introductions to <em>Debates in Digital Humanities</em> from 2012 to 2023. They were then in charge of a brief discussion, so they identified a few keywords and ideas, and brought up questions. Let me summarize a bit per year:</p> <ul> <li>2012: “The Big Tent” metaphor was of course something that stood out but also the mention of the coding or not coding debate and move towards making and building; accessibility; Is DH saving the Humanities?; Twitter; turn to inclusivity; and the semi-public peer review of the book.</li> <li>2016: Move from “big tent” to an expanded field noting that the big tent metaphor itself seemed a bit US/Anglo-centric; the division of the articles; and the decentralization of DH acknowledging our influence on other fields and how other fields influence DH.</li> <li>2019: DH as vectors; a request for accountability and empathy in our practices; focus on the present times.</li> <li>2023: Focus on the moment to recalibrate the sense of the future, asking ourselves how DH matters beyond itself; social justice in DH; more collaboration with ethical implications.</li> </ul> <p>We had a wonderful conversation about all that they found interesting while they made connections from one year to another themselves. This navigation through the years gave them a good sense of where we are at now, the type of further readings we will cover in class during the semester and the care they have to show on their project(s). How are they going to “take action in the present” in drafting their project documentation? How can they apply these notions and methods in their home disciplines?</p> <p>In order for them to see the variety and diversity of approaches of DH to scholarship in the present moment, the following day we discussed <em>Programming Historian</em> and <em>Reviews in DH</em> as two resources in which they can see DH in action. They loved both journals! They had some questions about how the reviews are done in <em>Reviews</em>, which I kindly explained, and offered a few suggestions for <em>PH</em> after reading:</p> <ul> <li>Sichani A-M, Baker J, Afanador-Llach MJ and Walsh B, “Diversity and inclusion in digital scholarship and pedagogy: the case of The Programming Historian,” Insights, 2019, 32: 16, 1–6;</li> <li>Isasi et al. “A Model for Multilingual and Multicultural Digital Scholarship Methods Publishing: The Case of Programming Historian,” in Multilingual Digital Humanities ed. by L. Violla and P. Spence, Routledge, 2023: 17-30.</li> </ul> <p>In the following days, they have to search for project examples that are related to our readings and each student will chose and teach a workshop from <em>Programming Historian</em>, with a low-tech approach first.</p> <hr/> <p>Some food for thought for all of us, left by a student, more or less like this: “So how is everyone going to participate in DH and these debates and methods and practices if all these books (on <em>Debates</em>) are in English only?”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="course"/><category term="course"/><category term="bibliography"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[a summary of a class discussing how DH has changed in the last ten years plus a showcase of methods and DH examples]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is the goal of this DH course?</title><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/my-DH-class-perspective/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is the goal of this DH course?"/><published>2025-01-16T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-16T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/my-DH-class-perspective</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/my-DH-class-perspective/"><![CDATA[<p>Second class in the books, with more students! Even if it cut some of the time I had planned to use on the readings (more below), I decided to start with a repeat of the <a href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/first-day-of-class/">“We Data” exercise</a> with the two new students that joined today, and had the two previous student guide the conversation around data. Once again one student had a harder time than the other in thinking about themselves in data, but that didn’t stop them from creating and sharing data with some thoughts and questions about it.</p> <p>After getting to know each other better, we switched to knowing the course better. I had assigned them two articles for today, with the request to annotate them in any way they find useful<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>:</p> <ul> <li>Dombrowski, Quinn. “Does Coding Matter for Doing Digital Humanities?” <em>The Bloomsbury Handbook to the Digital Humanities</em>, edited by James O’Sullivan, Bloomsbury Academic, 2022. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5040/9781350232143">https://doi.org/10.5040/9781350232143</a>.</li> <li>Walsh, Brandon. “The Three-Speed Problem in Digital Humanities Pedagogy” <em>What We Teach When We Teach DH</em>, edited by Brian Croxall, Diane K. Jakacki, University of Minnesota Press, 2023. https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.5749/jj.1410591.21</li> </ul> <p>I led the conversation to model what a discussion can look like in this course, but also to see if they had already connected the readings to their personal experiences and to make sure that I made clear the purpose of the course: To learn about the importance of drafting a workflow and documentation about one own’s research, by learning with examples relevant to them, and kind of at their own pace; rather than learning programming or multiple tools and methods.</p> <p>Quinn’s article is fantastic for this purpose, specifically, I believe -and my students thought so too-, because it has clear examples of what a workflow is (Quinn, did you write the steps of my dissertation?) and makes an argument for documenting all the steps in said workflow for maintenance, re-use, and sustainability; without getting too much into detail. At the same time, they are very clear about where the argument is coming from (coding or not coding?). I added a few questions along the way to help them connect ideas with their work. For example, I asked: “If I requested it, could you tell me how the files in your computers are organized?” They all responded “yes I can!” but upon asking further, they all confessed that they had to figure how to do it themselves and will probably not work forever. With this, it kind of clicked that writing detailed documentation of those decisions would help them in the future, specially if they need to share files with someone else.</p> <p>Brandon’s article, on the other hand, gave me the perfect entryway to assuring them that</p> <ul> <li>we won’t do buttonology to learn tools for the shake of learning them <ul> <li>A student brought up how the article made her think differently about the worth of learning a tool first, then figuring out how to use it for research</li> </ul> </li> <li>we won’t run over content until all of us are on the same page <ul> <li>Collaboration and sharing knowledge and skills is necessary in DH so we will help each other</li> </ul> </li> <li>designing a workflow will be applicable to their own research and interests, so they can create documentation about something that is really going to help them this semester: MA thesis research, dissertation, a final paper in another class, a hobby!</li> </ul> <p>Overall, a great second day of class with good questions to start the course will clear expectations from everyone - and for me to give more thought about content for future class sessions. I am very grateful to Quinn and Brandon for crafting these two thoughtful articles that are very accessible to anyone who might come into DH without having heard much about it or not having a clear idea of what we do.</p> <p>Next day we are going to chat about how DH has changed over time and I look forward to that discussion.</p> <div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"> <ol> <li id="fn:1"> <p>I am using Perusall for this collective, online annotation assignments because it is the one that is integrated in Canvas at my institution. I told the students that I am not going to be checking all the stats the tools give me, focusing only on the conversation we can have instead. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> </ol> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="course"/><category term="course"/><category term="bibliography"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[a summary of a second day of class]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Day of Foundations in DH: We Data</title><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/first-day-of-class/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Day of Foundations in DH: We Data"/><published>2025-01-15T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-15T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/first-day-of-class</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2025/first-day-of-class/"><![CDATA[<p>Finally! This semester I am teaching a Digital Humanities course for graduate students at PSU called “Foundations in DH”. In a series of blog-posts that I hope to write regularly and inspired by the writing of my friend <a href="https://walshbr.com">Dr. Walsh</a> I will share my experience and thoughts throughout the semester.</p> <p>The course, overly summarized, will prepare the student to create their own project workflows and document relevant pieces of it (data organization, dictionaries, management plans, context, timeline, budget if “needed”, etc.) while they get to explore the many possibilities of DH. Since it is the first time and I have a very tiny class, I am going to target the content to students’ interest as much a possible. For now that looks like: Data modeling and documentation, Latinx DH, Multilingual DH, digitale Geisteswissenschaften (DH in German), and GlobalDH. Yay!</p> <p>Today was the usual “introductions” day but with a twist, thanks to “<a href="https://walshbr.com/blog/we-data-an-icebreaking-activity/">We Data: An Icebreaking Activity</a>” by Brandon. We are sharing our experiences and I loved this idea for an icebreaker by creating/curating and then sharing information in the form of data. And I think my students loved it!</p> <p>Using a few guiding questions that prompt the identification, description, collection, analysis, and distribution of data, students shared a few facts about themselves: full name, country of origin, degree, year in grad school, pets, number of languages, religion, hobbies, fun facts, etc. They also chose to narrate the data, adding some context or clarification when needed.</p> <p>After learning about each other, we had a brief and general discussion of the activity using, again, Brandon’s questions:</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>What is data?
What is it not?
What was hard?
What did you learn?
How did it feel to represent yourselves in this way?
</code></pre></div></div> <p>As I was expecting, I had both the “easy” and “hard” responses here. The student that is used to having to create datasets after interviews didn’t have a hard time putting together some information in this format. The student who is more accustomed to narrative formats was taken a bit by surprised when asked to “categorized” the information of the paragraph that one usually shares the first day of class. But both were happy with the learning process. At the same time, they didn’t dislike having to represent themselves in this way because it helped them focus more on the type of information they were going to share.</p> <p>None of the students thought much about sharing sensitive data and, although we all shared personal data, they thought they could share anything they chose to, regarding the class as a safe space to do so. This fact I believe will do for interesting conversations as we move on to reading about digital archival practices, data modeling or presenting data.</p> <p>I will definitely incorporate this activity in other teaching spaces, adapting it to the goal of the sessions (ie can I use it for a network analysis workshop?).</p> <p>As I like doing, I modeled the exercise with some of my own data as well, sharing it in narrative form and trying to contextualize the information in connection to the course.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th style="text-align: left">Name</th> <th style="text-align: left">Pronouns</th> <th style="text-align: left">Country of origin</th> <th style="text-align: left"># of languages</th> <th style="text-align: left">Languages</th> <th style="text-align: left">Years in the US</th> <th style="text-align: left">Degree</th> <th style="text-align: left">Graduation Year</th> <th style="text-align: left">Current Title(s)</th> <th style="text-align: left">Hobby #1</th> <th style="text-align: left">Hobby #2</th> <th style="text-align: left">Hobby #3</th> <th style="text-align: left">?</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td style="text-align: left">Jennifer Isasi</td> <td style="text-align: left">she/her/ella</td> <td style="text-align: left">Spain</td> <td style="text-align: left">3</td> <td style="text-align: left">Spanish, English, Basque</td> <td style="text-align: left">13</td> <td style="text-align: left">Hispanic Studies with DH</td> <td style="text-align: left">2017</td> <td style="text-align: left">Assistant Research Professor of Digital Scholarship and Director of the Digital Liberal Arts Research Initiative</td> <td style="text-align: left">Dancing</td> <td style="text-align: left">Stories</td> <td style="text-align: left">LEGO</td> <td style="text-align: left">?</td> </tr> </tbody> </table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="course"/><category term="icebreaking"/><category term="course"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[a summary of a first day of class]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with advanced image components</title><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/advanced-images/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with advanced image components"/><published>2024-01-27T11:46:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-27T11:46:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/advanced-images</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/advanced-images/"><![CDATA[<p>This is an example post with advanced image components.</p> <h2 id="image-slider">Image Slider</h2> <p>This is a simple image slider. It uses the <a href="https://swiperjs.com/">Swiper</a> library. Check the <a href="https://swiperjs.com/demos">examples page</a> for more information of what you can achieve with it.</p> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/9.jpg" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/9.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/7.jpg" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/7.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/8.jpg" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/8.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/10.jpg" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/10.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/12.jpg" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/12.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> <h2 id="image-comparison-slider">Image Comparison Slider</h2> <p>This is a simple image comparison slider. It uses the <a href="https://img-comparison-slider.sneas.io/">img-comparison-slider</a> library. Check the <a href="https://img-comparison-slider.sneas.io/examples.html">examples page</a> for more information of what you can achieve with it.</p> <img-comparison-slider> <figure slot="first"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/prof_pic.jpg" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/prof_pic.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <figure slot="second"> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/prof_pic_color.png" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/prof_pic_color.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </img-comparison-slider>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="images"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what advanced image components could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with geojson</title><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/geojson-map/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with geojson"/><published>2024-01-26T17:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-26T17:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/geojson-map</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/geojson-map/"><![CDATA[<p>This is an example post with some <a href="https://geojson.org/">geojson</a> code. The support is provided thanks to <a href="https://leafletjs.com/">Leaflet</a>. To create your own visualization, go to <a href="https://geojson.io/">geojson.io</a>.</p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">```</span><span class="nl">geojson
</span><span class="sb">{
  "type": "FeatureCollection",
  "features": [
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {},
      "geometry": {
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [
              -60.11363029935569,
              -2.904625022183211
            ],
            [
              -60.11363029935569,
              -3.162613728707967
            ],
            [
              -59.820894493858034,
              -3.162613728707967
            ],
            [
              -59.820894493858034,
              -2.904625022183211
            ],
            [
              -60.11363029935569,
              -2.904625022183211
            ]
          ]
        ],
        "type": "Polygon"
      }
    }
  ]
}</span>
<span class="p">```</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Which generates:</p> <pre><code class="language-geojson">{
  "type": "FeatureCollection",
  "features": [
    {
      "type": "Feature",
      "properties": {},
      "geometry": {
        "coordinates": [
          [
            [
              -60.11363029935569,
              -2.904625022183211
            ],
            [
              -60.11363029935569,
              -3.162613728707967
            ],
            [
              -59.820894493858034,
              -3.162613728707967
            ],
            [
              -59.820894493858034,
              -2.904625022183211
            ],
            [
              -60.11363029935569,
              -2.904625022183211
            ]
          ]
        ],
        "type": "Polygon"
      }
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="charts"/><category term="maps"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included geojson code could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with echarts</title><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/echarts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with echarts"/><published>2024-01-26T16:03:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-26T16:03:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/echarts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/echarts/"><![CDATA[<p>This is an example post with some <a href="https://echarts.apache.org/">echarts</a> code.</p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">```</span><span class="nl">echarts
</span><span class="sb">{
  "title": {
    "text": "ECharts Getting Started Example"
  },
  "responsive": true,
  "tooltip": {},
  "legend": {
    "top": "30px",
    "data": ["sales"]
  },
  "xAxis": {
    "data": ["Shirts", "Cardigans", "Chiffons", "Pants", "Heels", "Socks"]
  },
  "yAxis": {},
  "series": [
    {
      "name": "sales",
      "type": "bar",
      "data": [5, 20, 36, 10, 10, 20]
    }
  ]
}</span>
<span class="p">```</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Which generates:</p> <pre><code class="language-echarts">{
  "title": {
    "text": "ECharts Getting Started Example"
  },
  "responsive": true,
  "tooltip": {},
  "legend": {
    "top": "30px",
    "data": ["sales"]
  },
  "xAxis": {
    "data": ["Shirts", "Cardigans", "Chiffons", "Pants", "Heels", "Socks"]
  },
  "yAxis": {},
  "series": [
    {
      "name": "sales",
      "type": "bar",
      "data": [5, 20, 36, 10, 10, 20]
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre> <p>Note that this library offer support for both light and dark themes. You can switch between them using the theme switcher in the top right corner of the page.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="charts"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included echarts code could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with chart.js</title><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/chartjs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with chart.js"/><published>2024-01-26T01:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-26T01:04:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/chartjs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2024/chartjs/"><![CDATA[<p>This is an example post with some <a href="https://www.chartjs.org/">chart.js</a> code.</p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">```</span><span class="nl">chartjs
</span><span class="sb">{
  "type": "line",
  "data": {
    "labels": [
      "January",
      "February",
      "March",
      "April",
      "May",
      "June",
      "July"
    ],
    "datasets": [
      {
        "label": "# of bugs",
        "fill": false,
        "lineTension": 0.1,
        "backgroundColor": "rgba(75,192,192,0.4)",
        "borderColor": "rgba(75,192,192,1)",
        "borderCapStyle": "butt",
        "borderDash": [],
        "borderDashOffset": 0,
        "borderJoinStyle": "miter",
        "pointBorderColor": "rgba(75,192,192,1)",
        "pointBackgroundColor": "#fff",
        "pointBorderWidth": 1,
        "pointHoverRadius": 5,
        "pointHoverBackgroundColor": "rgba(75,192,192,1)",
        "pointHoverBorderColor": "rgba(220,220,220,1)",
        "pointHoverBorderWidth": 2,
        "pointRadius": 1,
        "pointHitRadius": 10,
        "data": [
          65,
          59,
          80,
          81,
          56,
          55,
          40
        ],
        "spanGaps": false
      }
    ]
  },
  "options": {}
}</span>
<span class="p">```</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>This is how it looks like:</p> <pre><code class="language-chartjs">{
  "type": "line",
  "data": {
    "labels": [
      "January",
      "February",
      "March",
      "April",
      "May",
      "June",
      "July"
    ],
    "datasets": [
      {
        "label": "# of bugs",
        "fill": false,
        "lineTension": 0.1,
        "backgroundColor": "rgba(75,192,192,0.4)",
        "borderColor": "rgba(75,192,192,1)",
        "borderCapStyle": "butt",
        "borderDash": [],
        "borderDashOffset": 0,
        "borderJoinStyle": "miter",
        "pointBorderColor": "rgba(75,192,192,1)",
        "pointBackgroundColor": "#fff",
        "pointBorderWidth": 1,
        "pointHoverRadius": 5,
        "pointHoverBackgroundColor": "rgba(75,192,192,1)",
        "pointHoverBorderColor": "rgba(220,220,220,1)",
        "pointHoverBorderWidth": 2,
        "pointRadius": 1,
        "pointHitRadius": 10,
        "data": [
          65,
          59,
          80,
          81,
          56,
          55,
          40
        ],
        "spanGaps": false
      }
    ]
  },
  "options": {}
}
</code></pre> <p>Also another example chart.</p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">```</span><span class="nl">chartjs
</span><span class="sb">{
  "type": "doughnut",
  "data": {
    "labels": [
      "Red",
      "Blue",
      "Yellow"
    ],
    "datasets": [
      {
        "data": [
          300,
          50,
          100
        ],
        "backgroundColor": [
          "#FF6384",
          "#36A2EB",
          "#FFCE56"
        ],
        "hoverBackgroundColor": [
          "#FF6384",
          "#36A2EB",
          "#FFCE56"
        ]
      }
    ]
  },
  "options": {}
}</span>
<span class="p">```</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Which generates:</p> <pre><code class="language-chartjs">{
  "type": "doughnut",
  "data": {
    "labels": [
      "Red",
      "Blue",
      "Yellow"
    ],
    "datasets": [
      {
        "data": [
          300,
          50,
          100
        ],
        "backgroundColor": [
          "#FF6384",
          "#36A2EB",
          "#FFCE56"
        ],
        "hoverBackgroundColor": [
          "#FF6384",
          "#36A2EB",
          "#FFCE56"
        ]
      }
    ]
  },
  "options": {}
}
</code></pre>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="charts"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included chart.js code could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with TikZJax</title><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2023/tikzjax/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with TikZJax"/><published>2023-12-12T22:25:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-12T22:25:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2023/tikzjax</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2023/tikzjax/"><![CDATA[<p>This is an example post with TikZ code. TikZJax converts script tags (containing TikZ code) into SVGs.</p> <script type="text/tikz">
\begin{tikzpicture}
    \draw[red,fill=black!60!red] (0,0) circle [radius=1.5];
    \draw[green,fill=black!60!green] (0,0) circle [x radius=1.5cm, y radius=10mm];
    \draw[blue,fill=black!60!blue] (0,0) circle [x radius=1cm, y radius=5mm, rotate=30];
\end{tikzpicture}
</script>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="diagrams"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included TikZ code could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with bibliography</title><link href="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2023/post-bibliography/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with bibliography"/><published>2023-07-12T13:56:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-12T13:56:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2023/post-bibliography</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jenniferisasi.github.io/blog/2023/post-bibliography/"><![CDATA[<p>This post shows how to add bibliography to simple blog posts. We support every citation style that <a href="https://github.com/inukshuk/jekyll-scholar">jekyll-scholar</a> does. That means simple citation like (missing reference), multiple citations like (missing reference), long references like (missing reference) or also quotes:</p> <blockquote><p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing elit,<br/>sed do eiusmod tempor.</p><p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipisicing.</p><cite>(missing reference)</cite></blockquote> <p>If you would like something more academic, check the <a href="/blog/2021/distill/">distill style post</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="bib"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an example of a blog post with bibliography]]></summary></entry></feed>